number 24 meditation number 24 the ninth
refuge now the ninth message commitment
is to encourage other people to take
corrections okay the ninth refuge file
refuge and I just want to talk about
that I was in Singapore Singapore has
probably the best follow-up programs in
the world of all the Dharma Jenny Wong's
group because of Jenny won't they
probably have the best follow-up every
almost a couple times a week you can do
follow-up in Singapore with somebody or
you can go visit a nursing home or if
they do it's very regular and it's very
organized like Singapore people are so
organized and not like anybody else in
the world so then I said so Denny what
are you guys doing you know this week
and she said we're having a sharing you
know and I didn't know what she's
talking about it's a move what's a
sharing and she says you know we get up
and we share and I said what is here
she's nobody shared deep they are you
know we we shared this yeah I said all
your teaching people she said no to look
at me like this you know we share we
don't teach when I write Oh
that's cool you know get your Michael TJ
Singapore people and share and it feels
much better right it feels it means you
get to say something also and I'm I
don't get up and say I'm the best person
in this room I know everything I also
know Tibetan grammar you know we don't
until I will teach you you know and but
if you go to Singapore they will say I
will share with you my experience you
share with me your stream and and let's
help each other
you see it's mutual kind of thing so
this refuge valve by the way what's the
picture
this lady is telling not sharing okay
and her friend is irritated stop
teaching me you know okay stop telling
me by the way this is very common when
people go home after a retreat at time a
month and they tell their family true
the truth they should I could say
anything will do is wrong
you see Michael said only I understand
in this whole family only I understand
you know everybody should do like me you
know and will quickly become the most
unpopular person in your family okay go
with your family there's a family
gathering and people see you they will
they will go the other way I hope she
doesn't tell me what to do okay so I
think with this message bow number nine
okay encouraged means people warnings
okay if people are interested then share
if they're not interested don't bother
them
okay one of the most irritating things
in the world is a new tourist you know
if you want to alienate other people if
you don't want them to learn anything do
like that missionary become missionary
right like you must believe me when I
believe and I don't like it okay nobody
likes it I don't like it someone starts
talking to me like that there are some
groups in America they come to your
house they bang on your door and and
they welcome the door and they say do
you believe you know everything believe
in one this one oh no good then you
can't get them to get that foot in your
house it's like the camel and you can't
get them out when I was in the temple in
New Jersey they used to come and I told
Rivage I said this people keep coming
back he said to bank them just a bit
though we had fun and they were pretty
much fell away don't irritate other
people with your Buddhism okay you can
talk about you know cell phones but be
careful they might put you into a mental
hospital don't don't go crazy share with
the people who want to know but don't
bother people
okay so when we do meditation number 24
look and think about how to share
sweetly like Singapore people and you
can think about dua dua
over to I'd tell people you know do I
share or do I tell okay okay do I have
this bad habit of pushing my religion on
other people
okay and I think that's important for
the refuge Val okay